tmcc.edu 2018-12-21

# Disclaimer - Truckee Meadows Community College

Truckee Meadows Community College policy respects the privacy of all website visitors to the extent permitted by law. This online privacy statement is intended to inform you of the ways in which this website collects information, the uses to which that information will be put, and the ways in which we will protect any information you choose to provide us.

### TMCC Privacy Notice

In accordance with institutional policy and the [U.S. Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)](http://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html), Truckee Meadows Community College vigorously protects the privacy of student education records. The institution does not release private records of individual students, such as grades and class schedules, without prior written consent of the student.

As permitted under federal law, the sole exception to the above practice is the release of "directory" information considered to be public in nature and not generally deemed to be an invasion of privacy. At Truckee Meadows Community College, the following categories are defined as "directory" information: student name, address, telephone number, semesters of enrollment, full-time/part-time status, degree(s) awarded, emphasis field(s) and date(s) of graduation.

Students have the right to request non-disclosure of directory information. If they do not restrict release of this information, it is probable that the information will be released or disclosed. Truckee Meadows Community College uses directory information for non-commercial, educational purposes, such as to mail notices to students about changes in policies, services, or opportunities. Directory information may also be provided for commercial purposes to businesses affiliated with the institution, honor societies, the alumni association and foundation, or other individuals for purposes that may be beneficial to students. The institution exercises discretion in responding to requests for directory information and may or may not provide such information when requested, depending on the intended purpose of the request. The institution does not sell or rent student information for a fee.

It is important to consider carefully the potential consequences of restricting the release of directory information. If a student restricts release for non-commercial educational purposes, the institution will be unable to place the student's name in publications such as honors and graduation programs; to confirm graduation and dates of attendance to potential employers; to verify enrollment with organizations such as insurance companies; or to send notifications about specialized scholarships without the express written authorization of the student.

If, after due consideration, you wish to restrict the release of directory information, please download the Privacy Notice for Printed Materials form. The authorization can be mailed, faxed, or delivered in person to the office indicated on the form. A copy of the authorization form is also available in the class schedule and College Catalog. This directive will apply permanently to your record until you choose to reverse it by submitting a written authorization to the Admissions and Records Office.

### Network Traffic Logs

In the course of ensuring network security and consistent service for all users, TMCC employs software programs to do such things as monitor network traffic, identify unauthorized access or access to nonpublic information, detect computer viruses and other software that might damage TMCC's computers or the network, and monitor and tune the performance of the TMCC network.

In the course of such monitoring, these programs may detect such information as email headers, addresses from network packets, and other information. Information from these activities is used only for the purpose of maintaining the security and performance of the TMCC's networks and computer systems.

Personally identifiable information from these activities is not released to external parties without your consent unless authorized by the TMCC President or required by law.

### Web Server Logs

The Truckee Meadows Community College website routinely collects and stores information from online visitors to help manage and improve service. This information includes the pages visited on the site; the date and time of the visit; the Internet address (URL or IP address) of the referring site; the domain name and IP address from which the access occurred; the version of browser used; the capabilities of the browser; and search terms used on our search engines.

This site makes no attempt to identify individual visitors from this information; personally identifiable information is not released to external parties without your consent unless authorized by the TMCC President or required by law.

### Google Analytics and AdWords

The College and its agents use the [Google Analytics Platform](https://www.google.com/analytics/) in the operation of the Site. Google Analytics is a service provided by the third-party company Google, Inc. The College may use the full Google Analytics package and may gather demographic data, IP address information, referrer information, click-through rates, traffic sessions, page views, metric information, and Google Analytics Advertiser Features in furtherance of Site effectiveness and performance. Google Analytics collects data about your web traffic via cookies or anonymous identifiers, in addition to other mechanisms.

The College and its agents may also use Google's remarketing feature in [AdWords](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/6008942?hl=en&rd=1), an advertising platform, to reach Users who have been to the Site before through marketing initiatives. The College uses this functionality as is necessary in its marketing operations. This means that Google may use Google cookies to display our ads to you across other websites or platforms based on your interactions or past visits to the College's Site.

### Cookies

Cookies are pieces of information stored by your Web browser on behalf of a website and returned to the website on request. This site may use cookies for two purposes: to carry data about your current session at the site from one Web page to the next, and to identify you to the site between visits.

If you prefer not to receive cookies, you may turn them off in your browser, or may set your browser to ask you before accepting a new cookie. Some pages may not function properly if the cookies are turned off.

Unless otherwise notified on this site, we will not store data other than for these two purposes in cookies. Cookies remain on your computer, and accordingly we neither store cookies on our computers nor forward them to any external parties.

Unless otherwise notified on this site, we do not use cookies to track your movement among different websites and do not exchange cookies with other entities.

### Information Voluntarily Provided by You

In the course of using this website, you may choose to provide us with information to help us serve your needs. For example, you may send us electronic mail (through a mailer or a Web form) to request information, you may sign up for a mailing list, or you may send us your address so that we may send you an application or other material.

Any personally identifiable information you send us will be used only for the purpose indicated. Requests for information will be directed to the appropriate staff to respond to the request and may be recorded to help us update our site to better respond to similar requests. We will not sell, exchange or otherwise distribute your personally identifiable information without your consent, except to the extent required by law. We do not retain the information longer than necessary for normal operations. Each Web page requesting information discloses the purpose of that information.

If you do not wish to have the information used in that manner, you are not required to provide it. Please contact the person listed on the specific page, or listed below, with questions or concerns on the use of personally identifiable information.

### External Links

Truckee Meadows Community College website provide links to other World Wide websites or resources. We do not control these sites and resources, do not endorse them, and are not responsible for their availability, content, or delivery of services. In particular, external sites are not bound by the college's online privacy policy; they may have their own policies or none at all. Often you can tell you are leaving a TMCC website by noting the URL of the destination site.

If you have questions about this site, its collection of information, and its online privacy statement, please contact webmaster@tmcc.edu.

**See Also:**  Email Privacy, Security and General Use Disclaimer
